Guide to the Stanford Nurse Alumnae Records SC0360
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Nurse Alumnae records
1896-1987
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Nurse Alumnae
Stanford University. School of Nursing
SC0360
10 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
The Stanford Nurse Alumnae group serves as a liaison among nurse alumnae, faculty and the University and to perpetuate Stanford University School of Nursing's traditions of nursing: nursing excellence in clinical care, education, administration and research.
Nursing schools; Nursing -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Alumni and alumnae; Stanford Nurse Alumnae; Stanford University. School of Nursing
- Original accession, Accession ARCH-1989-064
  - Stanford University Announcement: Nursing, 1925 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanford School of Nursing, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stanford School of Nursing, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stanford School of Nursing Courses for Graduate Nurses Announcement, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Stanford School of Nursing Supplementary and Postgraduate Courses Announcement, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Stanford School of Nursing Announcement, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford School of Nursing Announcement of Courses, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing Annual Announcement, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing Annual Announcement 1942-43, 1942 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing Annual Announcement 1943-44, 1943 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing Announcement 1944-45, 1944 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing Annual Announcement 1946-47, 1946 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing Annual Announcement 1947-48, 1947 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing t 1948-49, 1948 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1949-50, 1949 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1950-51, 1950 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1951-52, 1951 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1952-53, 1952 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1953-54, 1953 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1954-55, 1954 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1955-56, 1955 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1956-57, 1956 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1957-58, 1957 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1958-59, 1958 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1959-60, 1959 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1960-61, 1960 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1961-62, 1961 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1962-63, 1962 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1963-1964, 1963 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1964-65, 1964 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1965-66, 1965 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1966-67, 1966 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1967-68, 1967 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1968-69, 1968 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Stanford University School of Nursing 1969-1970, 1969 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1970-71, 1970 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Stanford University Bulletin School of Nursing 1971-72, 1971 June (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Education for Nursing at Stanford University (7 copies), undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Planning for the Future of Nursing Education at Stanford University, 1972-1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - University Hospital Committee, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - History as it was Written (2 copies), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The Study of Nursing at Stanford: A Report of the Exploratory Phase, 1969 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Stanford University School of Nursing Self Evaluation Report, 1966 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Stanford University School of Nursing Self-Evaluation Report, 1969 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Stanford University School of Nursing Progress Report, 1971 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Progress Report Faculty Study Group, 1969 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Stories of Childhood and Youth May Cooper, 1878-1905 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten Letters, Hospital Center News, Season's Greetings, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Cutouts about Stanford Nursing, 1948-1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lane and Stanford Nurses' Alumnae, 1936-1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Cutouts. Stanford Nurses Club, USNS Mercy, 1938-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Stanford School of Nursing Class Program Cards, Record of Yard Instruction, Financial Statement, Constitution of the Student Body of the Stanford School of Nursing, Stanford Nurse Alumnae Membership, 1934-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Various Letters and Photos, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Book I Stanford Nurses Club Stanford Alumni Association, 1896-1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Book II Stanford Nurses Club Stanford Alumni Association, 1943-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scrap Book II, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Scrap Book III, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Scrap Book IV, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Scrap book V, 1980 May-1982 May (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Book VII, 1982-1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Book VI, up to 1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-1989-081
  - History of Stanford School of Nursing Vol. 2, 1930-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence/Miscellaneous, 1925-1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Nurse Alumnae: By-Laws, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional material, Accession ARCH-1989-106
  - Lane Hospital History (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Student Faculty Party, "The Faculty Meeting", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Student Handbook, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History of Stanford University School of Nursing, vol. 2, 1930-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cooper-Stanford Medical School brick, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1994-063
  Scope and Contents
  Includes images of Lane Hospital in San Francisco, nursing instructors, Lane Medical Library, nursing students, patients, students' residence, and the Convalescent Home for Children on Stanford campus and its patients.
  - Photograph album kept by Noreen Elliott, 1919-1922 (Box 1)